We're ruined!
No more free Wi-Fi.
Hey. Ki-jung!
Yeah?
The woman upstairs
finally put a password on iptime.
A password?
Did you try "123456789"?
Yeah. doesn't work.
Try it in reverse.
I told you. it doesn't work.
Shit! Then no text.
no Ka- Talk. no nothing?
That's right.
Hey. Kim Ki-taek.
Fucking don't pretend to sleep.
What do you think?
Our phones are all shut off...
Wi-Fi is all shut off...
Fucking what's your plan?
Huh?
- Hey. Ki-woo.
- Yes. father?
For Wi-Fi. you have to hold it up high.
Search out every corner.
Damn stink bugs!
Hey. here! I got it!
Really? You got it?
Yeah. you're getting it too?
This one. 'coffee land 2G.'
A new cafe opened up nearby?
Why can't I get it?
Come up here closer.
Hey kids?
- Is it working?
- Yeah.
Then check on Ka-Talk.
Pizza Time said they'd contact me.
Ok. hold on.
Here it is. Pizza Time.
Wow. check this out!
At this speed. I think
we can finish all these today!
We're getting paid today. right?
- She does it standing.
- She's a pro!
What's that? Fumigation?
They still do that kind of thing?
Guess so.
Shut the window.
Leave it alone.
We'll get free indoor fumigation.
And get rid of the stink bugs.
Right. too many stink bugs these days.
Oh. that smell!
I told you to shut it!
Should I shut it?
What's the problem exactly?
For example. have a look here.
You see this god-awful line?
And why is there a crease here? Huh?
Why is this sticking out?
That means you didn't finish folding it.
On inspection. 1 out of 4 were in this condition.
Roughly. 1 out of 4 are rejects.
So. you're really docking 10% off our pay?
Considering the fail rate.
the penalty is very minor. don't you think?
But. our pay is so low already!
Aren't you being too harsh?
You look here.
This is not a minor issue.
Do you know how much damage
these faulty boxes cause to our brand image?
Brand? You don't even have
a proper box folder. shit!
What did you say?!
Boss.
This is all because of that guy. isn't it?
What are you talking about?
That other part-time help.
he went AWOL. right?
Just when you got that huge. important
group order from that church.
How do you know these details?
Who told you?
My sister knows the guy.
He's always been a bit strange.
He has a bad reputation around here.
Therefore. Boss.
The 10% penalty.
we'll accept it.
In return...
In return?
Any thought of hiring
new part-time help?
Sis. we need more hired help!
Fire that other part-timer.
Hand him the termination penalty.
I'll come for the formal interview tomorrow.
What time works best best for you?
Hold on a minute.
I need to think about this.
Then. let's start with the
payment for these boxes.
So we've all gathered here today...
to celebrate the partial
reconnection of our phones
and the bountiful Wi-Fi!
That bastard !
So early in the evening!
Why haven't you put up the
'No Urinating' sign?
I told you to!
No. a sign like that only encourages
them...those drunkards.
At least yell at him!
No. don't shout.
"Please don't piss!"
Fuck!
Huh?
Is that Min-hyuk oppa?
Mister. what are you doing?
That's not the toilet.
That is Min-hyuk.
Hey. punk!
What... what are you staring at?
Come over here. you little shit.
Get a fucking grip!
Your friend has spunk!
University students have
real spirit. Spirit!
Unlike you. big brother.
But. is he coming here?
Were you expecting him?
No.
Hello!
Min-hyuk. you've come!
Hey. what's up?
Have you been well. sir?
- Of course.
- Hey. what's the ocassion?
I texted you.
You didn't see it?
So sorry... during your meal.
No. no. we weren't eating.
- You've been well. Ki-jung?
- Yeah. and you?
You should've asked to meet up.
Why come all the way here?
Because of this.
This is for you.
but it's so darn heavy.
Really? Put it down here.
Wow. what is this?
I told my grandfather that
I'm seeing Ki-woo
and he insisted that
I take this to him.
Wow. is this an artscape stone?
You can also
call this a zen stone.
Wow. you know!
My grandpa has collected these stones
since his military academy days.
Now downstairs. upstairs.
living room. the study...
they're all filled with these.
This stone is said to bring material fortune
and promotion to the family...
Hey. Min-hyuk!
This is really symbolic!
For sure! Truly. this is very timely.
Isn't it?
Please relay our deepest
gratitude to your grandfather.
You could've brought
something to eat.
Hey. what was that called?
Artscape stone?
You collect those rocks too?
Hey. thanks to that rock. I got to
see your parents. They looked healthy.
They're plenty healthy.
just out of work.
Is Ki-jung also home bound these days?
Not taking classes?
It's not that she doesn't want to.
It's that she can't.
She's cute. huh?
Wow. is that her?
The one you're tutoring?
Park Da-hye.
High school sophomore.
Why don't you take my place
as her English tutor?
What are you talking about?
It's tutoring for a rich family.
They pay very well.
And. she's a good kid.
While I'm studying abroad.
take good care of her.
What about your close
university friends?
Why ask a deadbeat like me?
Why do you think?
Even the thought of it makes me sick.
My wolf-like bastard classmates
fawning all over Da-hye?
It's revolting.
You into her?
Hey. I'm serious.
Year after next. when she enters university.
I'm going to officially ask her out.
Until then. take good care of her.
If it's you. I can leave with trust.
Thanks for trusting me. but...
do you want me to
pretend I'm a university student?
Ki-woo. think about it.
Two years before and after
your military service
you took the university entrance exam 4 times.
Grammar. vocabulary.
composition. conversation...
Honestly. when it comes to English
you can teach it 10 times better than those
alcohol binging college pricks.
- I guess so.
- Sure!
But. will that family accept me?
I'm not even a university student.
We'll just BS a little.
It'll be alright! First of all.
you're going on my recommendation. and...
how should I describe her mother...?
The madame's a bit simple.
Young and simple.
Simple?
What do you mean?
I don't know... Anyway. all's good.
It's been good for me.
So you're doing this. ok?
Ok. then.
Hey. I hear Ki-jung is very
talented with her hands.
...good with things like Photoshop.
With skills like this. why are you
rejected to art schools every time?
Wanna die?
Excuse me. it's non-smoking here.
Yeah. sure. Give me that.
Ok.
Now the finishing touch ...in scarlet red.
Wow. I wonder if Seoul National University
has a major in document forgery.
Ki-jung would be admitted
top of her class!
So true. huh?
Her skills!
Our boy's going for a job interview and
no words of encouragement?
Son!
I'm proud of you.
Father!
I don't think of this
as forgery or crime.
Because. for sure. I'm going to
this university next year.
So. you've got a plan!
I think of it as having produced
this document just earlier.
Subtitle
www.movieddl.me
Who is it?
Are you... Da-hye's mother?
How do you do?
I'm here on teacher
Min-hyuk's recommendation.
Oh. right.
Come on in.
Thank you.
Hello!
How do you do. Madame?
I'm just someone who
works here. Come this way.
The garden is so nice.
The interior is nice. too.
You know the architect
Nam-goong? He's very famous.
This is the house
that he lived in.
He built all this himself.
Now... as you can see.
this is just a family home with children.
This way.
Please sit here and wait.
I'll bring her right up.
Yes.
Madame?
He's here.
The tutoring candidate.
I don't need documents like these.
You're here on teacher Min-hyuk's
recommendation. anyway.
As you must know. teacher Min-hyuk
is such a "brilliant" person.
Da-hye and my satisfaction with teacher
Min-hyuk was very high.
...independent of her grades.
Do you know what I mean?
Yes.
Things were very good.
Honestly. Da-hye and I wanted to stick with him
until her university exam next year.
But. suddenly he tells us
he's leaving to study abroad.
So. excuse me for being blunt.
but... honestly
if you're not up to teacher
Min-hyuk's level. then...
there's really no point.
So. anyway. what I wanted to say is...
for your first lesson today.
would you mind if I sat in?
I want to see it "full time"
to see how you run your lessons.
Is it okay with you?
Are you sure about #24?
You just spent a long while solving those
problems before going back to #24.
Right?
Yes.
If this was the actual exam and this the first question.
you'd be screwed from the beginning.
Look at this. Your pulse is
pitter-pattering all over the place.
The heart cannot lie.
What is an exam. exactly?
It's all about cutting through.
The flow! Lose that rhythm
and you're finished.
The correct answer to #24?
I'm not interested.
How you punch through the entire exam...
How you dominate it
that's what I'm interested in.
In real battle. it's all about the spirit.
Spirit.
Understand?
Your salary will be paid out
about this time every month
Lessons every Mon/Wed/Fri.
2 hours each. Is that okay?
As for the amount...
I was going to match teacher Min-hyuk's
rate but adjusted it for inflation.
Thank you.
How about a proper introduction?
Da-hye's English tutor.
We'll call him teacher Kevin.
Teacher Kevin!
If you get hungry during your lessons.
let me know anytime.
If you need anything. just ask her.
She's the house expert. more than me!
She knows every nook and cranny...
Da-song ! Watch the head!
I'm so sorry! He startled you?
So. cute. Da-song?
Yes. our youngest.
Da-song. come say hi!
This is teacher Kevin!
This is an Indian arrow.
We ordered it directly from a U.S. website.
He's been fanatic about
Indians since last year.
Indians?
He seems to have mania traits.
Well. he's just so aloof
and easily distracted.
He can hardly sit still!
So. last year I enrolled him
in Cub Scouts...
hoping he'd learn some
restraint and focus.
But. look at him.
He came back worse!
Not sure if he was influenced by his
Cub Scout teacher who is crazy about Indians.
The very spirit of Cub Scouts originates
from the native American Indians.
That's a good thing!
Teacher Kevin.
you were a Cub Scout. too?
Yes. I'm a total Scout
by disposition.
Our Da-song is a total artist by
disposition. Have a look.
This is really symbolic.
It's very intense!
Intense. right?
Of course. you are very insightful.
That's a drawing of
a chimpanzee. right?
It's a self-portrait.
Sure enough!
From the perspective of grown-ups
Da-song's expressive genius
eludes their understanding.
Maybe that's why we've been through
so many art teachers.
And none of them could last
more than a month.
And also. Da-song is
so difficult to control.
- Madame?
- Yes?
Someone just came to mind.
What was her name?
Jessica! Right. Jessica...
Among the junior classmates of my cousin
is someone named Jessica.
What was her Korean name?
Anyway. after studying applied arts at the
Illinois State University
she just returned to Korea.
Illinois... and?
Jessica has a reputation for her unconventional
teaching style and command over children.
...a very fresh approach in this field.
But. even with her
unconventional methods...
Her students get in to the best art schools
- from middle school to university.
Oh my... I'm very curious.
What is she like?
Would you like to meet her?
But. I hear it's very hard
to get an appointment with her.
Hold it.
Jessica. Only child. Illinois. Chicago
Senior classmate Kim Jin-mo.
Second cousin.
Look how he's stained the table cloth
with drippings of banchan. gochujang and rice
in this mosaic-like arrangement.
These have repeating patterns. too.
Gochujang is red. grains of the rice.
Well. anyway...
He's showing his Basquiat-esque feel.
And he's only 9 year old!
Hmm... you've piqued my interest.
Since I'm sure teacher Jessica gets all this
I'll leave you two to continue
and I will start my lesson with Da-hye.
Teacher Jessica. see you next time.
Yes. thank you.
So if you see over there. shall we say...
Da-song's eccentric disposition?
Da-hye.
Shall we start with question #38?
Teacher.
Yeah?
Did you know that with
Da-song... it's all a pretense?
Huh? What do you mean?
It's all a show. A show!
Acting all genius. that 4th dimension
stuff - it's all a pretense.
An artist cosplay.
Da-song?
You know that thing...
when someone stops in his tracks and looks up
as if stricken with some random inspiration?
Like when someone stops to stare at the
clouds for 10 minutes... stuff like that?
You do know!
He gives me the goose bumps!
He pretends that everyday life
gets him down.
Makes me want to puke. really.
So. Da-song is like that.
But. what's that got to do with
you solving those problems?
I mean... well. I'm just saying.
Ok then. with that in mind...
What you just expressed about
Da-song was very interesting.
So. let's try some
English composition.
Only. be sure to use the word
"pretend" at least twice.
Then. can I ask you a question?
Sure.
That teacher Jessica.
Is she really your cousin's junior classmate?
What do you mean?
She's your girlfriend. right?
No. I met her today for the first time!
Teacher Jessica was
really pretty. wasn't she?
You don't find her attractive?
You saw her earlier?
Sure. she's pretty.
You can say she's attractive.
Yeah.
I knew it!
You are interested in her.
Da-hye...
If we had to use the rose metaphor
for teacher Jessica
then. Da-hye. you are...
- Let's solve the problem.
- Ok.
Please understand that my boy
has trouble keeping still.
I understand.
Da-song!
Da-song. get up!
Come on. Da-song!
It's in your butt!
- Mrs. Park. please leave us.
- What?
I never teach with parents in the room.
But today is our first day.
and as you can see. he's...
Please wait downstairs.
Park Da-song?
Da-song!
- Madame?
- Huh?
Would you like some
plum vinegar drink?
Whah?
Mixed with some honey
...to ease your tension.
Yeah. that would be great.
- Over here!
- Yes?
We can do it this way.
Mix two glasses and
take it up to Da-song's room.
You're not a parent.
so you can go in!
Oh. that's right!
Then I'll report back on
how they're doing in there...
I should've done this earlier!
What is it?
Are they out?
Yeah.
So. you're finished already?
Mrs. Park?
Please come and sit next to me.
Da-song. you wait upstairs.
Hurry it up!
Da-song just drew this.
I see...
I want to speak with Mrs. Park alone.
Oh. but she's our...
No. please excuse us.
Mrs. Park. I told you earlier that I'm doing advanced
studies in art psychology and art therapy?
Yes. yes.
Did something happen to
Da-song in the first grade?
To be honest.
before deciding whether
I can take on Da-song.
I will need to know more about this.
But. so sudden to talk
about this right now...
What to do?
It's alright. then.
Normally. the lower-right region of a drawing
is called the "schizophrenia zone."
Psychotic symptoms
often reveal themselves here.
Oh. phrenia...
Look here.
Da-song drew these
unusual shapes. right?
I see.
Over there. it's the same!
It's the same. right?
Yes. that's correct.
Similar shapes in the same zone.
Do you see it now?
Yes.
I saw that drawing every day
...at every meal.
But. I had absolutely no idea!
Please calm down. Keep calm!
This is all a black box
into Da-song's mind.
Would you like to open that
black box with me. Mrs. Park?
I want to open it. teacher.
Then. Mon/Tue/Thus/Fri.
2-hour sessions every week.
And this is not your basic tutoring.
but more art therapy. right?
Of course.
Therefore. my rate will need to be
considerably higher.
Are you okay with that?
I'm more thankful for it!
Oh my. that must be Da-song's dad.
Honey. Da-song's new art teacher is here.
Her name's teacher Jessica.
from Illinois.
Jessica ! This is Dong-ik.
- How do you do?
- Oh. hi.
Please take good care of Da-song.
Is the lesson over?
Yes. just finished.
- Driver Yoon.
- Yes?
- Are you ok with time?
- Yes. I'm ok.
Why not give the teacher a lift home?
Sure. we don't want her walking down
alone at night. right?
Of course.
Teacher Jessica?
Since you're already in the car.
may I drive you all the way home?
- Which neighborhood?
- No. that's fine
You can just drop me off
at the Hyehwa station.
Thank you.
I don't mind if your home is far.
- My shift is finished. anyway.
- I'll just get off at the Hyehwa station.
...looks like it's going to rain.
Forget the subway. let's go all the way
in this Mercedes Benz.
I'm supposed to meet my boyfriend
at the Hyehwa station. exit #3.
I see.
Dad. did you drive a lot of Mercedes Benzes
when you worked as a designated driver?
Mercedes Benzes? Not then. but I did a lot
when I worked as a valet in Daechi-dong.
Oh right. you worked as a valet!
After our fried chicken business went bust. and
before the opening of our Taiwanese castella bakery.
In that 6-month window?
No. it was after our
castella bakery went bust.
Then. we're moving ahead with it?
I finished setting up the
Mercedes Benz S-class already.
Then. we are moving ahead with it.
Wow. it's so symbolic here.
Look Father. we're eating in a
drivers' cafeteria. of all places.
Indeed. a drivers' cafeteria!
Eat as much as you want
there's plenty!
Why are you being so generous?
Kids are the ones buying!
My son. have some more. Eat up!
Yes. sir.
Eat your fill!
What did you do to Mrs. Park yesterday?
What?
She was freaking out!
Saying she was so moved and stuff.
Fuck. I don't know!
I researched art therapy
on the internet and BS'd a little.
Suddenly. she started weeping!
Crazy bitch.
I couldn't believe it!
Oh. you're home. Honey?
Did you have dinner?
Why. is something wrong?
Is the housekeeper out?
She's walking the dogs.
Honey.
This was under my car seat.
Driver Yoon. you crazy bastard.
What is this?
I'm so sorry. honey.
I didn't know driver Yoon
was this kind of person.
Don't you pay him very well?
Is this bastard skimping
motel costs so he can save up?
He must be a pervert.
He likes it in the car
better than motels.
Oh. that's disgusting.
How in his own boss' car!
A young guy's sex life is his
private business. That's all fine.
But of all places.
why in my car?
And if so. why not in his own front seat?
Why cross the line like that?
You're right.
Does dripping his semen
all over my seat turn him on?
You're right.
But. you know what's
strangest of all?
What?
If you have car sex
one might leave behind
a strand of hair. or an earring.
Right.
But how can you forget
your own panties?
So. true!
It's a hard thing to forget!
So. this raises suspicions
about this woman.
Are you getting this?
Oh my... like meth or cocaine?!
Shhh!
The kids...
What do we do?
What if anyone finds something
like white powder in your car?
Calm down. relax!
Relax.
For now it's just a supposition.
A reasonable suspicion.
But. nothing to call the police about.
Of course. not.
Silly for a busy guy like me to reprimand.
"Why are you banging someone in my car?"
That would be silly.
So instead...
Can you make up some harmless excuse
and let him go quietly?
Okay. sure.
No need to mention panties or car sex.
We don't need to stoop
down to that level. do we?
Surely not!
But. do you think driver Yoon might go online
to accuse us of wrongful termination?
Give him a good severance package...
You're fininshed?
Did Da-song do well today?
Yes. of course.
- So. lesson is finished?
- Yes.
Teacher. the last time you came.
our driver gave you a ride. right?
That's right.
This may be an awkward question.
but nothing happened then?
He was very friendly.
I asked him to just drop
me off at the Hyehwa station.
But. he kept insisting to
take me all the way home.
That jerk. he drove all the way to
your home. so late at night?
To reveal where you live?
No. I got off at the Hyehwa station.
Oh. you did well.
You did very well.
Jessica. nice!
Did something happen with him?
He won't be working for us anymore.
A slightly shameful incident.
What kind of incident?
Teacher. enough about that.
But I'm surprised. He was
so gentlemanly and cool.
Jessica. you're
too young and innocent!
You haven't experienced
a lot of people.
But. at the time. we were excited
to have such a young. hip driver.
But aren't drivers
better when a bit older?
That's true! They drive better
and have better manners.
The driver who worked for my uncle
was just like that.
Driver Kim -- he was
so congenial and nice.
I used to call him 'uncle' too.
when I was young.
You know a man like that?
Yes. he was so mild-mannered.
Right! My uncle recently
transferred to Chicago.
I wonder if he's currently
available.
Very interesting !
Could I meet him. maybe?
Oh. really?
Nowadays. I can't trust people.
If not recommended by someone
I know well. I really can't trust anyone.
But. if he's some one you've seen
since you were young. that's reassuring.
Do you really want to meet him?
I'm deadly serious.
Networking through
trusted referrals seems best.
How shall I describe it?
Safety belt of trust?
- This one's different.
- Here.
Oh. right.
And this one.
Looks like a touch screen now.
That's not touch.
It says you have to turn it.
Wow. this thing?
Sir?
You're taking your time?
This is a nice car.
Here it is!
Come over here.
He's in a meeting now.
Have a seat and wait here.
How do you do?
Nice to meet...
But. is it compatible
with mobile phones?
These are not compatible.
Requires more computing power.
This isn't a test drive or anything.
so don't be nervous.
I came out because I felt
so couped up at the office all day.
I understand.
Constant chatter. all that bother.
At least. the car should offer some peace.
Thank you.
You seem to know the roads very well?
Below the 38th parallel. I know
all the roads and side streets.
It comes naturally
after 30 years behind the wheel.
I respect those who work
in a single field for a long time.
Well. to be honest
this may be a simple vocation.
But. to get on the road every morning
with the head of a household
or with the company's
commander-in-chief
or with just a solitary man
each and every morning...
it's a companionship of a sort.
So. that's been my approach
each and every day.
The years sure pass quickly.
Sure enough.
your cornering is superb.
Well. the fundamentals
may look easy. but...
May look sheepish. but
inside she's a crafty old fox.
Sometimes she acts like
she owns the house!
Right.
She's lived there longer
than anyone in that house.
She was the housekeeper
to that architect. Nam-goong.
But then. she stayed on
to work for this family.
When Mr. Nam-goong moved out.
he introduced that woman to
Mr. and Mrs. Park. telling them...
"She takes great care of this house.
You should keep her!"
So. this is the case where the house ownership
changed. but not the housekeeper.
She's holding tight to this good job
and not letting go.
To surgically remove a woman like that.
we need some preparation.
Right. we need a plan.
I want some peaches.
I like peaches best.
Why not ask for some?
No peaches allowed in our home
- - forbidden fruit.
According to what
I heard from Da-hye.
she has a massively
serious allergy to peaches.
You know all that
fuzz on the skin?
If she goes anywhere near it.
she breaks out in hives
has trouble breathing.
asthma. a total meltdown!
No. no. no. No peaches anywhere
and it still happened.
That's what I'm saying!
Usually when I get symptoms like this
I run to my room and
medication takes care of it.
This was so sudden. I panicked and
couldn't remember where I put it!
Madame. this woman behind me.
is that...?
Oh. my! That's our housekeeper!
Then it's true!
Oh. what should I do?
I wasn't sure if that was really her.
I've only seen her a couple of times
in the living room.
You took this in a hospital?
A few days ago.
I went for my annual checkup.
I took a selfie for my wife.
and there she was. right behind me.
She's talking to someone on the phone?
I wasn't trying to eavesdrop...
but because I could hear her conversation!
- I couldn't help but...
- Cut. cut!
Father. your emotion is
too far up to here.
Bring it down to about here.
I couldn't help but overhear.
Compress it. then... boom!
What I'm trying to say is.
it's just that...
her voice was quite loud!
It's alright.
Just tell me. okay?
She said she just got
diagnosed with Active TB.
And was shouting
about it on the phone
as if so upset with herself.
she could hardly control herself!
Tuberculosis? Surely...
It's true! She was telling someone
on the phone that she had Active TB.
"Oh my! Do people still get TB these days?"
Oh my! Do people still get TB these days?
"Dad : "
"True... in the old days. people
used to buy Christmas seals for this."
"Feels like something from a bygone era..."
Search it on the internet.
Korea ranks # 1 for TB
among of all OECD countries.
"She was working. pretending
as if nothing was wrong !"
"With young children in the house
like Da-song."
And. with young children
in the house like Da-song.
A TB patient is doing dishes. preparing
food and coughing up bodily fluids...
Stop it. please!
If we get the chance.
this will be the finishing touch.
- Have a seat
- Yes.
Driver Kim.
Please don't tell any of this
to my kids or my husband. okay?
I understand.
If he hears I've harboured
a TB patient in our home
I'll be hanged and quartered!
Don't worry. Madame.
And if I may please say one thing
I have no hard feelings
against that woman.
I merely felt I had to speak up from
the perspective of public health and safety.
This could be misconstrued
as snitching...
You don't have to worry about that.
I'm not going to mention TB to her.
I'll just make up some other
excuse and dismiss her.
Simply and quietly.
It's the proven way.
This is the best way.
Well. then.
You...
washed your hands?
Driver Kim. do you know
a good braised-galbi place?
Not too far away.
Somewhere near by?
Sure.
- Then you'll be eating out?
- That's right.
Not sure why the craving
for braised-galbi today.
Our housekeeper used to make
really good braised ribs.
The one who quit
the day before yesterday?
My wife wouldn't even tell me why she quit.
Then again. housekeepers are plentiful.
We could just hire a new one.
Still. it's a shame.
She was a very good housekeeper.
I see.
She kept every corner
of the house in great shape.
And she knew
never to cross the line.
I can't stand people
who cross the line.
If just one negative point...
eating too much?
She said she always ate two servings.
Then again. she does do a lot of work.
Then she'd better find someone
quickly. A new housekeeper.
She's in big trouble right now.
With that housekeeper. our
house will be trashed in a week.
My clothes will start to reek...
My wife never had any talent for housework.
She's bad at cleaning.
and her cooking's god-awful.
You still love her. right?
Of course. I love her.
You have to call that love.
Then. take this.
THE CARE?
What is this?
I found out about them
just recently.
How to describe it?
It's a members-only service.
Provides experienced maids. caregivers
and drivers like myself to VIP customers like you.
A professional service of carefully
selected experts in their fields.
You can tell they're very exclusive
even from the card.
The design. too.
Driver Kim. how did you
come across this company?
They contacted me. because
of my veteran-status as VIP driver.
A kind of a scout offer?
But. when I got their call. I was already
scheduled to interview with you.
I see...
Your grace for turning down work with such a
prestigious company to work for me...
I'm forever indebted.
Fuck!
Anyway. I can give
this card to my wife. right?
Yes. that's why I brought it up.
No need to mention me.
You can tell her that you
found the company yourself.
Sure. why not.
Thanks to you I can
play the good husband.
On the back. there's a
number for consultations.
Tell her to call that...
Eyes on the road!
Hello. this is The Care's
senior advisor. Yeo Myung-son.
Yes. is this The Care's main office?
She's going to be very successful.
even as a con artist.
Isn't the tone of her voice great?
Takes after me.
From what I've heard.
it's a members-only service?
So. you're not currently
a member. I assume?
That's right. What steps
do I need to take?
We will need just a few documents.
Are you ready to write this down?
Your family register.
copy of your family's ID cards...
income documents to
verify your income level
and the title of your property. etc.
Our property title? Ah. yes.
Peaches!!
You have some too. teacher Kevin.
Thank you.
Miss. just leave it outside from now.
- Just knock.
- Yes.
Never enter during sessions!
Yes.
Park Da-song!
It's daddy!
Where are you?
Daddy!
Son!
Walkie talkies!
What do you like better.
me or the walkie talkies?
Da-song. what are you doing running out
during the middle of your lesson?
When did you buy all this?
It's no big deal.
Huh?
What is it?
What are you doing?
Da-song. that's enough!
Huh? It's the same!
They smell the same!
What nonsense! Go on up.
Teacher Jessica is waiting.
Teacher Jessica has a similar smell. too.
Then. do each of us have to
use different soaps?
Father. shouldn't we use
different laundry detergents. too?
And fabric softeners?
You mean. we run the laundry for each
person separately? Geez.
That's not it.
The stench is coming from
our semi-basement.
To lose the smell.
we have to leave this place.
Anyway. aren't we fortunate to be
worrying about something like this?
Sure!
These days. even an opening for
just one security guard
draws over 500 four-year university
graduates flocking to get the job.
And. our entire family
got hired full time!
That's right. Father!
Put all our 4 salaries together...
amount of wealth that's transferred from their
household to our's every month is no joke!
To the great Mr. Park.
let's offer a prayer of gratitude.
And. to Min-hyuk!
Because of Ki-woo's
amazing friend...
Thanks to him... Oh. fuck!
Just when we're trying to have a drink!
Oh. he's fuck'n dead!
Whoa. Kim Ki-woo's got the spunk!
You're over-doing it!
Here. use this instead.
Damn you!
Get a grip!
A grip!
Wow!
Total innundation!
Current weather is clear. over.
The clouds are moving in.
But they're not rain clouds. over.
Copy. over.
Currently your sister's lips are pouting like a duck's bill.
She's super annoyed. over.
Can't I just stay behind to study English?
Ask teacher Kevin to come over?
Hey! Just when we're about
to leave. why all the fuss?
Since we all decided to go.
let's go in a good mood!
Yeah. Da-hye. This is
no ordinary camping trip.
That's right!
As his older sister. you think it's ok
to miss your brother's birthday?
Absolutely. not!
Even I have taken the time out
of my very busy schedule to go.
Of course! If you don't go.
it'll be your loss.
Oh. right. You know the
beam projector?
The projecting thing?
Right. prepare the
outdoor beam projector.
And look for Da-song's
camping raincoat.
He get's excited when it rains.
You remember now?
Zoonie. Berry. and Fofoo.
Zoonie and Berry get this.
Yes. Natural Balance Original Ultra.
Right. and for Foofoo...
Kani Kamaboko.
The Japanese crab sticks.
Yes.
When you walk Zoonie.
give him a long leash.
He needs to run about in
all directions to feel satisfied.
He's like the canine version of Da-song!
Hey. son!
What are you doing lying out there?
Son of a gun.
Must be hot out.
This is lying at home.
gazing at the sky.
It's very nice.
Mom. want some water?
There's sparkling. right?
Ki-jung. want a bottle of water?
Whoa. telepathy!
Thank you.
Whoa. yeah!
! crash ! I
Wow. all these different kinds of liquor.
Father! I will pour you a special round.
Wow. this is rather picturesque.
The garden with the rain. shaaaa!
Us with the whiskey. shaaaa!
But. son. What's that yellow notebook
you've been carrying around?
This? It's Da-hye's diary.
Diary?
That's really disgusting.
Why are you reading her diary?
So we can understand each other
more deeply - in a positive way.
Fuck. You two dating?
I'm serious!
She likes me a lot too.
A while back...
Never mind.
When she enters university.
I intend to officially ask her out.
Seriously.
Oh. my son!
Then. this house will become
your in-laws' house?
Fuck. then I've been here
washing my in-laws' dishes?
Sure! Washing his father-in-law's underwear
and washing your daughter-in-law's socks!
I think... she's alright.
She's well-behaved.
Pretty-like. but
not spoiled rotten.
Well. now that we're projecting...
If Da-hye and I get married...
Your roles can be
hired out to actors.
She...
She did so many part-time gigs
at weddings last year.
I even had to catch bouquets
from bitches I've never met.
If you catch the bouquet.
they pay you extra $10.
That's how your acting
improved so much!
Acting is one thing. but
this family is so gullible. right?
The madame. especially.
You said it.
She's so naive.
and so nice!
She's rich. but still nice.
It's not. "rich. but still nice."
It's. "nice because she's rich!"
You know what I'm saying?
Hell. if I had all this money
I'd be even nicer!
Nicer!
That's true.
Your mom's right.
Rich people are naive.
Not tied up in knots all the time.
Kids from rich families are bright
and happy... no wrinkles.
It's the iron.
Money is the iron.
Those wrinkles are
all smoothed out.
Hey. Ki-woo.
You know that driver Yoon?
His sir name was Yoon. right?
The driver before me.
Yes. 'Yoon.'
He must be working somewhere now.
right? ...having found a job?
Sure. he must have.
He's of younger age
and of good physique...
Right. he must have
gone to a better employer.
Fucking hell. come on!
What's with her?
We're our biggest problem.
Let's just worry about us. okay?
Dad ! Dad ! Dad!
Please give us some
focus. okay? Us!
Not driver Yoon.
but to me. please!
Killer timing. huh?
Wow. Ki-jung goes. "Kyaaaa! !"
and the lightning goes. "Boooom ! !"
Hey. Jessica.
Bottoms up!
Hey. when I went up earlier.
and you were in the bath...
Bath. What about it?
How to put it?
You fit right in.
This rich house atmosphere suits
you very well. You're not like us.
Fuck off.
I'm serious!
Seriously. father.
Earlier...
she was lying back in the tub
watching TV
like she's lived here for years.
Speaking of which.
if this house became our's
assuming we lived here.
which room would you choose?
I'm asking which room you like best in this
masterpeice of the great architect Nam-goong.
Fuck. I don't know!
First let me live here.
then I'll worry about it.
We already live here. don't we?
Drinking in the middle of the
living room like this.
Right. this is 'living here.'
What's more to it?
This is our home right now.
It's cosy.
Are you cosy?
Are you feeling cosy?
Sure. but suppose Mr. Park suddenly
walked through that door right now.
Kim Ki-taek. this human being...
would scatter and hide like a cockroach.
Kids. you know at our house when
we turn on the fluorescent light at night.
how the cockroaches scatter and hide?
You know what I mean?
Fucking getting tired of listening to this...
- What? A cockroach?
- Yeah!
Huh? What are you doing?
Really?
Father. don't do it!
You're gonna kill somebody.
What the hell!
Fooled you.
Fooled you!
Father. you're so...
Ki-woo. you were fooled too!
Very real. wasn't it?
If it was for real.
you'd be dead. you fucker!
What the fuck?! Pet...?
What the...
Who is it at this hour?
Who is it?
Why. she...?
Fuck. that's that woman. isn't it?
Why is she here?
She keeps. keeps. keeps ringing.
Causing a ruckus in the neighborhood.
Who is it?
Oh. how do you do? I'm...
Um... the madame's not in. right?
What?
I worked here
for a very long time.
Above the monitor there.
you see the photo of 3 dogs. right?
Zoonie. Berry. Foofoo.
I get it. but what do you
want at this hour?
You're the woman who came as
my successor. Am I right?
Anyway...
I'm very sorry
to call on you so late.
It's just that...
I left something of mine in the
kitchen basement. Unintentionally.
When I quit. they pushed me out
so abruptly without proper notice.
Could you open the door?
What do we do?
This wasn't in the plan.
Please excuse me.
This way.
Yes. thank you.
Put your raincoat here...
I'll be very quick and leaving.
Oh. you did a lot of cooking there.
What a big mess to clean up!
But. what is it that
you left behind below?
Want to come down with me?
Just be back quickly.
Help me push this!
Pull it! From over there!
What?
Pull!
Harder!
Are you alright?
I startled you.
Thank you ! Thank you!
Thank you!
Honey!
What the hell?
Hey. you!
Honey!
Lady!
Honey. I'm here! Honey!
What the?
Honey. I'm fine.
Of course you're not!
I'm fine. really.
You are not fine!
I'm so hungry.
Take this. Take this.
How many days have you gone hungry?
Honey. you've been so very hungry!
It's okay. It's okay.
She's a good woman.
I got in. thanks to her.
It was the iron plate.
Iron plate for grilling meats.
It was wedged under the shelf.
No wonder.
Strangely. no matter how much I tried.
it wouldn't budge from the inside.
- What is this?
- I know you're freaked out.
I would be freaked out. too!
As fellow workers...
Right. sister Chung-sook?
How do you know my name?
Acutally. I still text
with the youngest. Da-song.
I came knowing that the family
would be away camping.
I wanted to speak with you. privately.
"Talking about."
Don't worry.
big sister Chung-sook.
I cut the wire to the
CCTV by the gate.
Nobody knows I'm here.
I did a good job. right sister?
Sister this. sister that...
Do you know me?
Sister. my name is
Moon-gwang.
This is my hubbie. Oh Geun-sae.
Say hello. honey.
So tasty!
But. why is your face like that?
Let's talk about that
another time.
So. while working here.
you looted the kitchen everyday
to feed your husband!
Not at all! What he eats.
I bought with my own salary!
That's really unfair.
Really unfair.
Then. how long has your
husband lived down here?
Oh my. hold on...
has it been 4 years?
4 years. 3 months
and 17 days.
Right. it's June now.
Four years ago. after Mr. Nam-goong
moved away to Paris
and before Mr. Park's family moved in
I brought my husband
down here. stealth-like.
Rich folks have secret bunkers
in case of a North Korean invasion
or to hide from creditors.
It's quite common.
Mr. Nam-goong was very embarrassed
about having made this secrete bunker.
Anyway. he never mentioned it
to Mr. Park's family.
So. only I knew about this...
I see. so that's how it all happened.
Now that I know. I have no choice
but to call the police!
No please. sister!
Please let's not do this to each other.
We're both needy people.
I'm not needy people!
But we are needy!
We have no home and no money.
All we have are debts!
Sister. please!
Even with 4 years of hiding.
debt collectors never let up.
They're still searching for him.
threatening to mangle him.
You borrowed from loan sharks?
It's all my fault. Me.
The castella bakery...
My Taiwanese Wangshui castella
bakery business went bust
and I fell into big debt.
Please take this.
What's this?
It's not much.
just a teeny weeny sum
but we'll send it to you
every month.
In return. just
once every two days
please put some
food together for him.
No. no. ...just
once every week.
There's even a refrigerator.
Just once a week.
You've got some nerve!
I'm calling the police.
Sister. sister!
What's that?
Wait...
Jessica?
Driver Kim?
What is this?
Father. my ankle!
Don't press it!
Father. my arm. my arm!
What are you doing calling me Father?
No wonder! I thought it so weird
starting with when driver Yoon was fired.
Hey!
Ma'am. let's talk things over.
What are you. a family
of charlatans or something?
So. little sister...
Little sister. my ass. you bitch !
Shut your pie hole!
I'm gonna send this video to Mrs. Park.
What do you think about that?
No reception here
in the basement. right?
- This basement has good signals.
- Fuck!
Ma'am. to be honest. because we so
desperately needed the...
Shut up! I don't want to hear it.
We're going down together!
Whether to the police or to jail.
we're going down together. everybody!
Woman ! Are you crazy?
If Mr. and Mrs. Park see that video.
how shocked they will be!
Those nice people...
what fault is it of their's?
Why do this to them?
Don't come any closer!
Or. I'll press the 'send' button.
Follow me.
Ma'am. please calm down.
Let's go up. honey.
Time for you to breath
some fresh air!
Honey. this 'send' button
is like a missile launcher.
What do you mean. honey?
If we threaten to push this button.
those people can't do anything.
It's like a North Korean rocket.
A North Korean missile button!
Today our beloved
Great Leader. Kim Jong-un
after witnessing the video of
the family of charlatans
was unable to contain
his shock and fury
at their wicked.
despicable provocations!
I've missed this. honey!
Therefore. our Great Leader
in this age of de-nuclearization
has commanded that the nation's
last remaining nuclear warhead
be driven down the throats
of this wicked family!
No one can imitate North Korean news
anchors like you ! I love you. honey!
With their stinking guts serving
as the last nuclear graveyard
our Dear Leader's wish to de-nuclearize
and bring world peace...
Hands in the air. assholes!
Higher!
You fucking family.
Husband?
Husband.
Wife?
Yes.
Son?
- Daughter?
- Daughter.
You low-lifes!
All you can think to do is.
to drink yourselves like dogs?
In the center of Mr. Nam-goon's living room
where his creative soul dwells?
You cretins!
What do you know of art?
What would they know?
On a sunny day. the two of us
would bask in the sunbeam
and in those moments.
we could feel his artistic touch.
Give it to me!
Good job! Delete it!
Careful! Don't press
'send' by accident.
Hello?
Listen. you know how to make
Chapa-guri. right?
Chapa-guri?
Chapa-guri is Da-song's favorite.
If you boil the water right away.
the timing will be perfect.
There's premium Korean sirloin
in the fridge. add that too.
Then. the camp...?
My god. what a disaster!
Nearby river overflowed and
caused a chaos of campers packing up.
Da-song was crying and throwing
a tantrum. refusing to go home!
Anyway. Chapa-guri to be served
immediately upon our arrival. okay?
Then. you're almost here?
8 minutes. according to the GPS.
Arrival in 8 minutes...
Hang up the phone
and put the water on.
What the hell is Chapa-guri?
Get up. quickly!
Move!
Father! I can't do this!
Why are you doing this?
Father!
Go up quickly! Quickly!
Hey. this!
You're home!
Da-song. look!
Let's eat Chapa-guri!
Da-song!
Madame!
Maybe you'll have to
eat the Chapa-guri.
Your sure?
No. wait. I can give it to
Das-song's dad.
There's premium
Korean sirloin in here.
The meat is cooked through to the center.
right? Medium well-done.
! Returning after a day's work. !
! I love you so much. Mr. Park! I
! Home from the office. I
I Mr. Park is off duty now. I
! Returning after a day's work. !
! I love you so much. Mr. Park! I
- What's this?
- Silence!
Honey. do you want some
Chapa-guri?
Da-song doesn't want it?
No.
No. I'm tired.
I'm going to bed.
Why are you staring at me like that?
It's embarrassing.
Mr. Park. Today. you
feed me again and house me.
Respect!
You do this every day?
Sure. I even send entire
sentences to thank him.
Someone of your age should know this.
What?
Morse Code.
That sensor's going batty.
Da-song should know it.
since he's a Scout.
It looks ridiculous.
doesn't it?
Why make so much fuss
trying to please a kid.
He's not even some kind of prince.
He's the youngest.
It's understandable.
Please understand.
Da-song is a bit...
shall we say. unwell?
He's receiving treatment for
trauma. art therapy. etc.
There was an incident.
What kind of...?
You believe in demons. don't you?
When he was in the 1st grade.
Da-song saw a demon in the house.
In the 1st grade. the day we had
his birthday party at home.
Late that night. when
everyone was sleeping
Da-song crept down to the kitchen
and took out the leftover cake.
The fresh whipped cream
on that cake was amazing.
Lying in his bed. he couldn't get
the cake out of his mind.
So. Da-song was sitting there
eating his cake when...
He screamed. "Kyaaaa ! ! !"
and I ran downstairs.
And. he was all...
his eyes rolled back. shaking in
convulsion. foaming at the mouth.
Have you ever seen your
own child go into a seizure?
No.
If you can't treat it within
15-minutes. it's all over.
That's the maximum time you have
to reach the ER. 15 minutes.
You can actually live like this?
In a place like this?
There's plenty more people
that live underground.
There's even more
if you count the semi-basements.
What are you going to do next?
You don't even have a plan. do you?
I just feel comfortable here. Just so.
It feels like I was born here.
Maybe. I had my wedding here. too.
As for the National Pension.
it doesn't apply to me.
You live out your old age
on nothing but affection.
So please. let me
continue to live down here.
Anyway...
My husband was away on business.
so I had to deal the utter chaos.
Since then. we've always
gone out for his birthdays.
Last year at my mother's house.
This year. the camping trip.
Da-song's dad says
all kids grow up like that.
He said. living in a house once possessed by a
demon is good for business and prosperity.
Actually. the business has been
very good the last few years.
Oh. man...
Stay here for now.
Zoonie. what's wrong?
Something under there?
What is it?
Damn it!
- Mom !
- Yeah?
- How could you?
- What?
I like Chapa-guri too!
How could you not ask me. even once?
Well...
Da-song didn't want it.
so you asked Dad. then ate it yourself.
Want to ask ajumma
to make some more?
No. that's not the point!
- Why are you fussing over ramen noodles!
- Why didn't you ask me?
Oh. stop it! Go to bed. quickly.
Go get changed into your pajamas.
This way!
Shhh!
Ki-jung is under there!
Hurry. hurry!
One. two. three!
Da-song. what are you doing?
Da-song!
He's crazy! Crazy!
Umbrella. please.
Hey. Park Da-song!
Son of a gun...
What the hell is he doing?
Da-song. it's time for bed !
Do you know what time it is?
Here.
Honey. take this.
Who do you take after to be
so stubborn? Look at this rain!
Channel 3 for emergencies!
Keep it turned on.
Give it to me.
I can't believe him.
Just leave him be.
He'll come in when he's tired.
Hey. Da-hye!
Why are you on your phone
so much? Go to bed.
Go on to your room and sleep.
We'll take care of things here.
This is the living room.
do you copy?
Copy. over.
Daddy is standing by for
emergencies. over.
Got it. over.
I suppose that tent is not going to leak?
That's U.S. made.
It'll be fine.
- Should we sleep here on the sofa?
- What?
We have a direct line of sight to the tent.
Good idea.
I'll feel much better.
Right?
Let's sleep while
watching over Da-song.
That son of a gun.
Wait a minute!
That stench is coming
from somewhere.
What stench?
Driver Kim's smell.
- Driver Kim?
- Yeah.
Not sure.
Really? You must know it already.
That stench that wafts through the car.
...how to describe it?
- An old man's smell?
- No no. it's not that.
Then. what is it?
Like old dried radish?
No.
You know that smell
when you boil a rag?
It smells like that.
Anyway. although he always seems
like he's about to cross the line
he never actually crosses it.
That's good.
- I'll give him credit for that.
- Yeah.
But that stink.
that crosses the line.
It powers right through
to the back seat.
What smell is it?
I don't know.
It's hard to describe in words.
But you sometimes
smell it on the subways.
It's been ages since I rode a subway.
People who ride the subway
have that unique smell.
Yeah.
Isn't this like the back seat of my car?
What if Da-song comes back in?
Don't worry!
I can just pull my hand back.
We shouldn't...
Clockwise.
Right.
You know where.
You still have those cheap panties?
Huh?
The one Yoon's bitch left behind.
If you wear those.
fuck. it'll turn me on.
Really?
Then get me some drugs.
Get me some drugs!
Take this instead.
You like it?
Emergency!
Emergency. over!
- Emergency!
- What?
What is it? Over.
Da-song. what's wrong?
I can't sleep. over.
So stop it and come in. okay?
Go sleep in your soft bed. over.
Right!
I don't want to. over.
Hey. Park Da-song.
Let's just sleep...
What happened back there?
What?
The people in the basement.
Well. I tied them up real tight.
What are you going to do?
Huh?
What are you going to do now?
What's your plan?
I've been wondering...
What Min-hyuk would do
in a situation like this.
Min-hyuk oppa would never be
in a sitution like this!
Look kids. we made it out
of there safely. right?
And besides us. nobody knows
what happened there. right?
So. nothing happened.
Understand?
My thoughts are...
because I have a plan
I want you two to just
forget about all this. okay?
Let's go home.
Let's go and wash up. ok?
What are you doing there?
Hurry down!
What is all this?
You stay put!
This is all sewer shit water.
Our window was left open?
Big brother!
Help me out with this!
Hey. Ki-woo!
Hey. Ki-woo. close the window!
The window!
Did you get electrocuted?
So dizzy.
Hold still. Keep still.
Shit. I feel dizzy.
Ki-jung. be careful!
Don't touch anything!
Honey. I must have a concussion.
I can't see you.
Honey. sister Chung-sook is
really a nice person.
But. she shoved me with her foot.
Repeat after me.
Chung-sook.
Ki-woo!
What at are you doing over there?
Huh?
H. E. L. P. M ...
Father?
Huh?
What is that plan from earlier?
What are you talking about?
Earlier. you said you had a plan.
What are you going to do? There...
in the basement.
Ki-woo. you know
what kind of plan never fails?
A 'Non-Plan.' A non-plan.
"No plan."
You know why?
If you make a plan.
life never turns out that way.
Look around here.
You think all these people planned in droves.
"Let's spend the night in a gym"?
But. look now.
Everyone's sleeping on the
gym floor. us included.
That's why people
shouldn't have plans.
With no plan.
nothing can go wrong.
If you start out without a plan. even if something
spins out of control. it doesn't matter.
Whether you kill someone
or betray your country.
None of it fucking matters.
Got it?
Father.
I'm sorry.
For what. son?
Everything.
All of it.
I'll take the responsibility.
What are you talking about?
Why are you embracing
that rock like that?
This?
It keeps clinging to me.
You'd better get some sleep.
Really!
It keeps following me.
Teacher Jessica?
Sorry to call on a Sunday morning.
Are you free for lunch today?
We're having an impromptu
birthday for Da-song.
Are you having a birthday party?
If you come too.
Da-song will be so very happy.
And have as much pasta. gratin.
and salmon steak as you want.
People will be here by 1pm
so be here by then.
And I'll count today
as one of your sessions.
You know what I mean?
See you later!
- Mom.
- Yeah?
For the impromptu birthday
should we invite teacher Kevin too?
Great idea! Why not?
Will you contact him?
Get some more sleep! You need to rest.
You had a rough day yesterday.
If you're doing a party.
won't you need to do the rounds?
Right. the wine shop.
supermarket. bakery. florist...
I already told driver Kim to hurry over.
I'll pay him overtime.
Perfect!
Everyone. calm down. calm down!
In the basement...
we have about 10 outdoor tables.
First take them all out.
then arrange them...
No. come to the window.
I need to show you.
With Da-song's tent in the middle
Set the tables outward in a curve...
A crane-wing formation!
Like Admiral Yi used. You remember
Battle of The Hansan Island?
Think of the tent as the
Japanese warship.
And our tables in the crane-wing formation
in a semi-circular fashion.
Then near the tent will be the
barbeque grill. firewood and such
all nicely arranged.
That will be great!
Bring your husband too!
Yeah!
And definitely no presents.
just come!
Dress code?
It's just an impromptu.
You can wear sweat pants if you want!
And absolutely no presents
Just come and enjoy the food.
You know already
my culinary skills.
Right! Right!
We'll drink wine in daylight.
If you would sing a song.
that'd be grand ! You know the one...
Ajumma. shhh!
He's still sleeping!
Today the sky's so blue.
and no yellow-dust pollution!
Thanks to all the rain yesterday.
Right.
So we traded camping
for a garden party. Deal!
It's lemons into lemonade.
Right. what would we have done
if not for the rain!
And definitely no presents.
I mean it!
Right. you've got the Mini Cooper so.
we'll just squeeze it into our garage.
Go on up!
Back it in tight.
Just don't block the Benz.
You're here!
It's been so long!
I told you no presents!
Oppa. you were thinking
of something else.
What?
While we were kissing. you were
thinking of something else.
No.
What do you mean. no?
You're still doing it.
Wow.
Everyone looks great. right?
Even for an impromptu.
they all look so cool
and so natural.
Da-hye.
Do I fit in well?
What?
Do I fit in well here?
Why? Where are you going?
I need to go down.
Just hang out with me.
I need to go below.
With all those boring people?
Can't you just hangout with me?
Not to those people.
Down lower.
Wow. what is that?
Really. I can't believe
we're doing this at our age.
It's embarrassing.
I'm really sorry. driver Kim.
It's at my wife's insistence.
I can't do anything about it.
But the concept is simple.
Teacher Jessica will carry out
the birthday cake in a little parade.
Then. we jump out
and attack teacher Jessica
swinging our Indian tomahawks!
Ah. right.
Just then. Da-song the good Indian
will jump out and we'll do battle.
Ultimately. he'll save the cake goddess Jessica.
and they will all give a big cheer.
Something like that.
Silly. isn't it?
I guess your wife likes
events and surprises.
Yeah. she does.
But she's particularly into this party.
You're trying your best. too.
Well. because
you love her. after all.
Driver Kim.
You know today is your work day.
Think of this as an
extension of your work. okay?
Have you been down there?
- No. not yet.
- Shouldn't we have a talk with them?
In a way that is
good for everyone?
Exactly!
We all got too fucking
worked up last night!
I know! And. dad was going on
about some plan...
- No. I'm going down there now.
- Hold on!
Take this down to them.
- They must be hungry.
- Right.
Let them eat first.
Come next time for sure!
Here you are. Jessica.
- This is too good !
- Yes. to die for!
I've got a special favor to ask.
What kind?
This is...
how to describe it?
Da-song's trauma
recovery cake?
So. it needs to be you who does this.
Today's highlight!
Excuse me...
Are you ok?
Mister! Mister!
Oppa? Oppa?
Da-song !
Happy birthday!
Congratulations!
Oh. fuck!
Stop!!
Sister Chung-sook!
Ki-jung!
Come on out. Chung-sook!
Stop the bleeding!
Push down on the wound!
Da-song!
Honey!
Let go!
Don't do it!
It hurts!
The ER!
Get the car out!
The car!
Driver Kim !
What the fuck are you doing?!
If we wait for the ambulance.
it'll be too late!
Dad. dad!
Stop pressing it.
Pressing it makes it
hurt more.
Give me the car key!
The car key!
Throw them !
Just throw me the key!
You okay?
Don't touch it!
How do you do. Mr. Park?
You know me?
Respect!
A month later when I opened my eyes.
the first face that I saw...
was that of a detective.
You have the right to an attorney...
He looked nothing
like a detective.
Is he laughing?
Just a moment.
Then. the doctor who looked
nothing like a doctor spoke.
That happens sometimes
immediately after brain surgery.
They keep laughing
for no reason.
Can you hear me?
Can you hear me. now?
Then. we have to do it again?
Do what again?
What I just did.
The Miranda.
You ! Um... have the right!
To remain silent!
Anything you say can and will
be used against you ...right? ...and
He keeps laughing. look!
Even when I heard how much
Ki-jung bled that day
even when I heard the words "document forgery."
"trespassing." "foul play. but self-defense"
...and that we were lucky to get away
with just a probation...
even when I finally got to
see Ki-jung's face...
Kim Ki-jung
Nov 20. 1996 -- July 1.2018
I kept laughing.
But. when I looked back
and watched all the news reports
I didn't laugh much at all.
Mom and I actually had no idea
where father was.
But. those detectives trying to tail us
still wore themselves out.
Eventually. when the news went quiet. and
the taills became less frequent
I started. from time to time.
to go up that mountain.
From up there. you get
a good view of the house.
That day. despite the cold.
I felt the urge to stay behind longer.
Dash - dash - dot - dot
dot - dot - dot - dash
dash - dash - dot...
Son!
You may be able to read this letter.
You were a Boy Scout. so just in case.
I am writing you a letter this way.
Have you recovered ok
from your injuries?
I'm sure your mom is
plenty healthy.
I'm doing fine
down here.
Though. I often cry
thinking bout Ki-jung.
Even now. what happened
that day seems surreal.
Feels like I dreamt it all.
Maybe I didn't.
That day. as I ran out the gate.
I suddenly realized
where I needed to go.
A house where such
grisly crime took place
is surely not so easy to sell.
I'm so sorry. Mr. Park.
So. I struggled to hold out in the
empty house until the new owners arrived.
Still. thanks to the
house being empty
What was her name?
'Moon' and 'Gwang?'
I was able to give lady Moon-gwang
a proper. dignified send off.
I gave her a tree-side burial which I hear are very
trendy these days. So. hell. I did my best.
But. those real estate sharks
sure are clever.
They hoodwinked some people
newly arrived in Korea and knowing nothing
and ultimately managed to
sell them the house.
With the parents working in a foreign company
and the kids attending a foreign school.
the family is usually out.
But. the goddamned housekeeper
stays glued here 24 hours a day.
Each time I go upstairs to the kitchen.
I put my life on the line.
It turns out that Germans don't eat and
drink just sausages and beer.
What a relief.
Passing the time down here.
everything starts to go hazy.
Today. at least. I was able to
write you a letter.
If I send out the letter
this way every night
maybe someday
you'll see it.
So long for now.
Ki-woo?
Is that you?
Yes.
Father.
I made a plan today.
It's a master plan.
I'm going to make money.
...loads of it.
University. career. marriage.
they're all fine
but I will first make money.
You'll see once you go in.
but it's very spacious.
Actually. we don't show
this kind of house to just anyone.
When I make the money.
I will first buy this house.
On the day we move in.
Mom and I will be in the garden.
Because the sunshine
is so nice there.
All you have to do
is come up the stairs.
Until that day comes. please
take very good care of yourself.
So long for now.